Guide to the Bookplate Collection, approximately 1890-1955
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Bookplate Collection
approximately 1890-1955
Underhill, Adelaide
Post, C. Gordon (Charles Gordon), 1903-
Smith, Margaret A. Pollard
12 cubic feet (27 boxes, 6 scrapbooks)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
The Vassar College Bookplate Collection consists of over 5000 items, most of which are mounted and indexed by type and name of owner and by designer, if prominent.
Administrative History
The Vassar College Bookplate Collection consists of several parts, the largest of which was gathered by Adelaide Underhill, VC 1888 and former Librarian at Vassar (1892-1928). In 1896 she commissioned from Edwin Davis French a bookplate for the Vassar Alumnae Historical Association. Using this bookplate for exchange, she built an impressive collection, which included examples of the work of the most important bookplate designers of the period and also early armorial bookplates. After her retirement, the collection came to Vassar permanently and continued to grow. It consists of over 5000 items, most of which are mounted and indexed by type and name of owner and by designer (if prominent).
Another part of the Collections is a collection of bookplates which the Vassar College Library has used over the years, primarily during the first half of the 20th century.
In 1949, Professor Charles Gordon Post gave a small collection of bookplates related primarily to the medical sciences.
The most recent addition to the Collection was the gift, in 1972, of the sizable collection of Margaret A. Pollard Smith, VC 1902 and also a former faculty member. Her collection was also strong in representing the important bookplate designers of the late 19th century and the first half of the 20th century.
Chronology
1896 Vassar College Bookplate Collection begun by Adelaide Underhill, VC 1888
1896 Edwin Davis French designs bookplate for the Vassar Alumnae Historical Association
1949 Professor Charles Gordon Post donates collection of bookplates related to the medical sciences
1972 Margaret A. Pollard Smith's collection of important late-19th and early-20th century bookplate designers donated
Scope and Content Note
The Vassar College Bookplate Collection consists of over 5000 items, most of which are mounted and indexed by type and name of owner and by designer, if prominent.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the
regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
without any additional restrictions.
Subject Headings
Names:
Bayros, Franz von, Marquis, 1866-1924; Bird, Elisha Brown; Chambers, Jay; Cole, Timothy, 1852-1931; Delehanty, Frances; Edwards, George Wharton, 1859-1950; Eve, G. W. (George William), 1855-1914; Fisher, William Edgar, b. 1872; French, Edwin Davis, 1851-1906; Fuertes, Katherine; Garret, Edmund H.; Harrod, Stanley; Hopson, William Fowler, 1849-1935; Ipsen, Ludvig Sandöe; Jameson, John W.; Jones, Dan Burne; Kipling, Rudyard, 1865-1936; Macdonald, Arthur Nelson, 1866-1940; Noll, Arthur H.; Noll, Maxwell H.; Pearson, Ralph M.; Pyle, Howard, 1853-1911; Rhead, Louis, 1857-1926; Sherborn, Charles William, 1831-1912; Smith, Sidney L.; Spenceley, J. Winfred (Joseph Winfred), 1865-1908; Stone, Pauline; Stone, Wilbur Macey; Vedder, Elihu, 1836-1923; Webb, Margaret Ely; Wheelan, Albertine Randall; Wheeler, Cleora; White, Raymond Perry; Williams, Gaar, 1880-1935; Williams, Helen Patterson; Yeats, Jack Butler, 1871-1957
Document Types:
Bookplates
VCL Categories
Printing and Publishing
Encoding Information
Finding aid encoded by Jason Kovari, 5 Feb 2009.
Acquisition Information
Bookplate Collection acquired through gifts of Adelaide Underhill, Charles Gordon Post and Harry J. Smith; collection acquired by exchange, as well.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in six series, and by type and alphabetically within each of those series.
Series List
- Series I. Adelaide Underhill Bookplate Collection, (Boxes 1-18)
  Boxes 1-17: Bookplates
  Box 18: Manuscript and Supporting Material
- Series II. Margaret A. Pollard Smith Bookplate Collection, (Boxes 19-20; Scrapbooks 1-4)
  Boxes 19-20: Bookplates and Supporting Materials
  Scrapbooks 1-4: Bookplates
- Series III. Charles Gordon Post Bookplate Collection, (Scrapbook 5)
- Series IV. Framed Materials, (Boxes 21-25)
- Series V. Vassar College Library Bookplates, (Box 26; Scrapbook 6)
  Box 26: Vassar College Library Bookplates and Supporting Material
  Scrapbook 6: Vassar College Library Bookplates
- Series VI. Bookplate Plates, (Box 27)
Container List
- SERIES I. Adelaide Underhill Bookplate Collection
  - Armorial bookplates, Individual Owners (alphabetical by owner), A-G (Box 1)
  - Armorial bookplates, Individual Owners, H-P (Box 2)
  - Armorial bookplates, Individual Owners, Q-Z (Box 3)
  - Foreign bookplates, French (Box 3)
  - Foreign bookplates, German (Box 4)
  - Foreign bookplates, Other -- Austrian, Czechoslovakian, Irish, Italian, Japanese, Russian, Scandinavian, Spanish (Box 4)
  - Unidentified (Box 4)
  - Designers and engravers (alphabetical by name), Bird- French (L) (Box 5)
  - Designers and engravers, French (M) - MacDonald (Box 6)
  - Designers and engravers, Noll - Wheeler (Box 7)
  - Bookplates of colleges, universities, and schools (alphabetical by name of institution), A - Hau (Box 8)
  - Bookplates of colleges, universities, and schools, Hav - U (Box 9)
  - Bookplates of colleges, universities, and schools, V - Z (Box 10)
  - Bookplates of public libraries (alphabetical by name of library), A-B (Box 10)
  - Bookplates of public libraries, C - Z (Box 11)
  - Bookplates of associations, clubs, firms, etc. alphabetical by name or organization) (Box 12)
  - Bookplates of the US. Government (alphabetical) (Box 12)
  - Miscellaneous old bookplates (not armorial; alphabetical by owner) (Box 12)
  - Modern bookplates, Individual owners (alphabetical by name of owner), A- C (Box 13)
  - Modern bookplates, Individual owners, D- H (Box 14)
  - Modern bookplates, Individual owners, I- O (Box 15)
  - Modern bookplates, Individual owners, P- S (Box 16)
  - Modern bookplates, Individual owners, T- Z (Box 17)
  - Bookplates of prominent persons (alphabetical) (Box 17)
  - Manuscript/Supporting Material (Box 17)
  - Adams Bookplate (Folder 18.1)
  - American Antiquarian Society (Folder 18.2)
  - American Society of Bookplate Collectors and Designers, etc. (Folder 18.3)
  - Correspondence (Folder 18.4)
  - Bird, Elisha Brown - Bookplates and correspondence (Folder 18.5)
  - Cole, Timothy - Catalog slips (Folder 18.6)
  - Cole, Timothy - biographical material (Folder 18.7)
  - Cole, Timothy- list of his bookplates, corrected (Folder 18.8)
  - Cole, Timothy- list of his bookplates, superseded (Folder 18.9)
  - Cole, Timothy- bookplates, miscellaneous (Folder 18.10)
  - Cole, Timothy- Exhibit catalog, Print Club of Philadelphia (Folder 18.11)
  - Cole, Timothy- Portrait of (Folder 18.12)
  - Cole, Timothy- Sonnets (Folder 18.13)
  - Cole, Timothy - Oliver Tonks article (Folder 18.14)
  - Cole, Timothy- his own bookplate, reproduction (Folder 18.15)
  - Correspondence- Baer, Carlyle S. re: Timothy Cole (Folder 18.16)
  - Correspondence- Timothy Cole's bookplate for Thaddeus R. Beal (Folder 18.17)
  - Correspondence- Timothy Cole, family of (Folder 18.18)
  - Correspondence- Deane, Ruthven (Folder 18.19)
  - Correspondence- Holman's Print Shop (Folder 18.20)
  - Correspondence- Leippert, James and Edwin re: Timothy Cole (Folder 18.21)
  - Correspondence- Lloyd, Mrs. Cyrus D. re: Timothy Cole (Folder 18.22)
  - Correspondence- Prince, Kimball re: Timothy Cole (Folder 18.23)
  - Correspondence- Randolph-Macon Woman's College re: Timothy Cole (Folder 18.24)
  - Correspondence- Printing House of William Edwin Rudge (Folder 18.25)
  - Correspondence- Swett, Carolyn Patten re: Timothy Cole (Folder 18.26)
  - Correspondence- Timothy Cole bookplate for James Carleton Young (Folder 18.27)
  - Correspondence- Miscellaneous re: Timothy Cole bookplates (Folder 18.28)
  - Biggs, Frances Richardson - bookplate by Timothy Cole (Folder 18.29)
  - Collins, Philip S. - bookplate by Timothy Cole (Folder 18.30)
  - Keats-Shelley Memorial, bookplate by Timothy Cole (Folder 18.31)
  - Knox, Leila Charlton, bookplate by Timothy Cole (Folder 18.32)
  - Radon, Herman Theodore, bookplate by Timothy Cole (Folder 18.33)
  - Smith, Margaret Pollard, bookplate by Timothy Cole (Folder 18.34)
  - Vassar College, bookplate by Timothy Cole (Folder 18.35)
  - Von Tiling, Johanna Erika Ruthven, bookplate by Timothy Cole (Folder 18.36)
  - Wednesday Book Club, bookplate by Timothy Cole (Folder 18.37)
  - Eunson, Robert, bookplate by Timothy Cole (Folder 18.38)
  - Fisher, William Edgar (Folder 18.39)
  - French, Edwin Davis-bookplates (1) (Folder 18.40)
  - French, Edwin Davis-bookplates (2) (Folder 18.41)
  - French, Edwin Davis-bookplates (3) (Folder 18.42)
  - Harrod, Stanley- bookplates, about (Folder 18.43)
  - Hill, Sara B.- bookplates and correspondence (Folder 18.44)
  - Hopson, William Fowler- biographical material (Folder 18.45)
  - Hopson, William Fowler- bookplates, Vassar College (Folder 18.46)
  - Hopson, William Fowler- bookplates (1) (Folder 18.47)
  - Hopson, William Fowler- bookplates (2) (Folder 18.48)
  - Hopson, William Fowler- his own bookplate (signed proof) (Folder 18.49)
  - Hopson, William Fowler- correspondence (Folder 18.50)
  - Jameson, John William- bookplates and correspondence (Folder 18.51)
  - Laboureur, G.E. – bookplates (Folder 18.52)
  - MacDonald, A.N.- bookplates (Folder 18.53)
  - Pearson, Ralph M.- bookplates and correspondence (Folder 18.54)
  - Rogers, Bruce- bookplates (Folder 18.55)
  - Smith, Ismael- bookplates (Folder 18.56)
  - Smith, Sidney L.- bookplates and correspondence (Folder 18.57)
  - Spenceley, J.W.- list of bookplates (Folder 18.58)
  - Thompson, Fred- bookplates (Folder 18.59)
  - Vbbelohde, Otto- bookplates (Folder 18.60)
  - Updike, Daniel B.- bookplates (Folder 18.61)
  - Wheeler, Cleora- correspondence (Folder 18.62)
  - Memorial Gift Bookplate for Ohio Alcove in American Library, Manila, P.I. (Folder 18.63)
- SERIES II. Margaret A. Pollard Smith Bookplate Collection
  - Individual Owners, A-F, mounted, designed by various artists (Folder 19.1)
  - Individual Owners, G-Z, mounted, designed by various artists (Folder 19.2)
  - Individual Owners, A-F, unmounted, designed by various artists (Folder 19.3)
  - Individual Owners, G-Z, unmounted, designed by various artists (Folder 19.4)
  - Individual Owners, A-J, unmounted, with correspondence (Folder 19.5)
  - Individual Owners, K-M, unmounted, with correspondence (Folder 19.6)
  - Individual Owners, N-Z, unmounted, with correspondence (Folder 19.7)
  - Individual Owners, mounted, armorial, designed by various artists (Folder 19.8)
  - Individual Owners, A-F, unmounted, armorial (Folder 19.9)
  - Individual Owners, H-Z, unmounted, armorial (Folder 19.10)
  - Unidentified Owners, unmounted, armorial (Folder 19.11)
  - Individual Owners, Unmounted unmounted, designed by F. Bayros (Folder 20.12)
  - Individual Owners, unmounted, designed by Flora-Belle Bolin (?) (Folder 20.13)
  - Individual Owners, unmounted, designed by E.D. French (Folder 20.14)
  - Individual Owners, Mounted, mounted, designed by A.N. Macdonald (Folder 20.15)
  - Individual Owners, mounted, designed by J.W. Spenceley (Folder 20.16)
  - Individual Owners, mounted, designed by J.W. Jameson (Folder 20.17)
  - Individual and Institutional Owners, mounted, designed by E.B. Bird (Folder 20.18)
  - Institutional Owners, mounted, designed by various artists (Folder 20.19)
  - Institutional Owners, A-L, unmounted (Folder 20.20)
  - Institutional Owners, M-Z, unmounted (Folder 20.21)
  - Institutional Owners, unmounted, armorial (Folder 20.22)
  - Institutional Owners, unmounted, designed by E.D. French (Folder 20.23)
  - Institutional Owners, mounted, designed by A.N. Macdonald (Folder 20.24)
  - Institutional Owners, mounted, designed by J.W. Spenceley (Folder 20.25)
  - Institutional Owners, mounted, armorial, designed by various artists (Folder 20.26)
  - Correspondence, miscellaneous (Folder 20.27)
  - Printed materials, miscellaneous (Folder 20.28)
  - Includes bookplates designed by Alfred J. Downey, Sara B. Hill, and Stanley Harrod; also armorial bookplates designed by various artists of the 18th and 19th centuries. (Scrapbook 1)
  - Includes bookplates designed by Timothy Cole, Sidney L. Smith, and W.F. Hopson; also early armorial bookplates and some miscellaneous pictorial plates. (Scrapbook 2)
  - Includes bookplates designed by O. U., Gayfield Shaw, and F. Bayros; also miscellaneous etched and process plates. (Scrapbook 3)
  - Includes bookplates designed by C.W. Sherborn, and W.P. Barrett; also a few miscellaneous plates. (Scrapbook 4)
- SERIES III. Charles Gordon Post Bookplate Collection
  - Scrapbook of bookplates, compiled by Charles Gordon Post (Professor of Political Science, 1933-1969), 1927-1946. The bookplates include those of libraries/doctors connected with Johns Hopkins University, Tulane Medical School, Vassar College, the University of Rochester, New York Public Library, Metropolitan Museum of Art, Columbia University, and the University of Virginia. (Scrapbook 5)
- SERIES IV. Framed Materials
  - Bookplate of George Burton Adams (Professor of History at Yale), by William Fowler Hopson, 1903 (Box 21)
  - Bookplate of George Edward Dimok, by Edwin D. French, 1904 (Box 21)
  - Bookplate of Vassar Alumnae Historical Association, by Edwin D. French, 1898 (Box 21)
  - Edwin D. French at work in his studio in the Adirondacks (Box 22)
  - Bookplate of Yale University--Edward Tompkins McLaughlin Memorial Prize, by Edwin D. French, 1896 (Box 23)
  - Bookplate of the Daughters of the American Revolution, by William Fowler Hopson, 1903 (Box 23)
  - Bookplate of the Society of Colonial Wars, Connecticut, by Edwin D. French (Box 24)
  - Bookplate of George Dudley Seymour, by William Fowler Hopson, 1894 (Box 25)
- SERIES V. Vassar College Library Bookplates
  - Alphabetical lists, 194? (three editions, two include annotations of type of plate) (Folder 26.1)
  - Affeld, Bertha Bacon, Fund (Folder 26.2)
  - Alumnae Collection (variations) Alumnae House (See: Backus, Mary Kountz, Memorial Library) (Folder 26.3)
  - Anable Alumnae Association, Gift of (designed by A.H. Noll, 1918) (Folder 26.4)
  - Andrews, Idelette E. (VC 1879), Memorial to (Folder 26.5)
  - Angell Fund [no label] (Folder 26.6)
  - Babson Fund [no label] (Folder 26.7)
  - Backus, Mary Kountz, Memorial Library [Library of Alumnae House, Vassar Biddle, Co.) (Folder 26.8)
  - Banfield, Edith (VC 1892), Memorial See: Class of 1892 Gift
  - Bedell, Mary (VC ex-1873), Collection (2 plates, pictorial plate designed by Antonia Nell, 1932) (Folder 26.9)
  - Benedict, Ruth Fulton (VC 1909), From the Library of (Folder 26.10)
  - Blewett, Avis H. and Lucy H., Gift of (Folder 26.11)
  - Blodgett, Minnie Cumnock (VC 1884), Collection (printed and designed by Merrymount Press, 1937) (Folder 26.12)
  - Blodgett, Minnie Cumnock (VC 1884), Hall of Euthenics (printed by Duttons, Inc.) (Folder 26.13)
  - Borden, Fanny (VC 1898), Collection Borden, Fanny (VC 1898) [personal plate] (Folder 26.14)
  - Bowen, Mary Elizabeth, Fund [formerly Edgar J. and Mary H. Bowen Fund] (Folder 26.15)
  - Breckinridge, Louise Dudley (VC 1936), In memory of (printed by Rudge, 1931) (Folder 26.16)
  - Brunn Archaeologial Collection, Gift of John D. Rockefeller (Folder 26.17)
  - Bryson, Ella Fitzgerald, In memory of (printed by Rudge, 1931) (Folder 26.18)
  - Buck, Gertrude, Drama Fund (printed by Todd, 1936, 1937) Buck, Gertrude, Memorial Fund (Folder 26.19)
  - Bush, Mary L., In memory of her mother, Mary L. Potter (printed by Rudge, 1930) (Folder 26.20)
  - Bush, Mary L., In memory of Wendell T. Bush (printed by Kalkhoff Press, 1941) (Folder 26.20)
  - Bush, Mary L., [personal plate] (designed by Elna de Neergaard, 1914) (Folder 26.20)
  - Bush, Wendel T., Gift of (Folder 26.21)
  - Butler, Elizabeth Rholdes (VC 1918), Gift of (designed by Edith Emerson) (Folder 26.22)
  - Canfield, Cora Elizabeth, Memorial to (Folder 26.23)
  - Carnegie Corporation, Grant from, to Department of Art (Folder 26.24)
  - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, Gift of (Folder 26.25)
  - Carnegie Library Endowment Fund [2 variants] (printed by Rudge; printed by Sequoia Pr.) (Folder 26.26)
  - Christian Association of Vassar college, Library of (Folder 26.27)
  - Churchill, Ruth Hornblower (VC 1908), Gift of (Folder 26.28)
  - Circolo Leonardo, Gift of (printed by Rudge) (Folder 26.29)
  - Cities and Towns Collection, 1898 See: Class of 1888
  - Class of 1869, Gift of, 1901, to the department of Math (Folder 26.30)
  - Class of 1870, Gift of, 1900, 30th Anniversary (Folder 26.31)
  - Class of 1871, Gift of, 1896, 25th Anniversary (Folder 26.32)
  - Class of 1873, Gift of, 1898, to Department of English (Folder 26.33)
  - Class of 1873, In memoriam, June 1873, June 1898 (designed by Margaret Armstrong; printed by Scribners) (Folder 26.34)
  - Class of 1875, 25th Anniversary Gift (Folder 26.35)
  - Class of 1877, Gift of, 1897, to the Department of English (Folder 26.36)
  - Class of 1878, 50th Anniversary Gift Class of 1878, Gift of, 1898, to the Department of Astronomy (Folder 26.37)
  - Class of 1879, Gift of, 1899 (Folder 26.38)
  - Class of 1881, 50th Anniversary Gift, June 1931 Class of 1882, Gift of See: Turgenev Collection (Folder 26.39)
  - Class of 1883 Library Fund (engraved by Dreka; printed by Bailey, Banks and Biddle, Co.) (Folder 26.40)
  - Class of 1884, Euthenics fund (Folder 26.41)
  - Class of 1884, Gift of (engraved by Dreka) (Folder 26.42)
  - Class of 1884, Music Fund (Folder 26.43)
  - Class of 1885, gift of [3 variants] (Folder 26.44)
  - Class of 1885 Greek Fund (printed by Rudge, 1936) (Folder 26.45)
  - Class of 1886, Margaret Pollock Sherwood Fund (Folder 26.46)
  - Class of 1887, The 1887 Library of Ethics Class of 1887 Ethics fund, in honor of James Monroe Taylor (Folder 26.47)
  - Class of 1888, Cities and Towns Collection (Folder 26.48)
  - Class of 1888, Gift of, 1898 (designed by R.R. Gentry, 1902; printed by Scribners, 1903) (Folder 26.49)
  - Class of 1888, Fund, in honor of Lucy Maynard Salmon (designed by Merrymount Press) (Folder 26.49)
  - Class of 1892, Gift in memory of Edith Colby Banfield (designed by William F. Hopson) (Folder 26.50)
  - Class of 1895, Gift of, to the Department of History, 1897 (Folder 26.51)
  - Class of 1895, Gift of, to the Department of Biology, 1897 (Folder 26.51)
  - Class of 1898 Library Fund (designed by F.W. Goudy) (Folder 26.52)
  - Class fo 1899 Memorial Fund (designed by Ralph Pearson, 1925) (Folder 26.53)
  - Class of 1900, gift of, 1903, to the Department of English (Folder 26.54)
  - Class of 1903, Gift of, to the Department of Zoology (Folder 26.55)
  - Class of 1906 Library Fund (designed by F. W. Goudy; printed by Coggeshall, 1938) (Folder 26.56)
  - Class of 1911 Library Fund (designed by G. Curtis Nobel; printed by Elson) (Folder 26.57)
  - Class of 1913 World War II Memorial (Folder 26.58)
  - Class of 1913 James Monroe Taylor Fund See: Taylor, James Monroe, Fund
  - Class of 1916 (Folder 26.59)
  - Class of 1920 (Folder 26.60)
  - Class of 1921 Library Fund (printed by Rudge, 1936) (Folder 26.61)
  - Class of 1926 See: Thomas, Mary Rogers
  - Cole, Timothy, Fund (designed by Timothy Cole) (Folder 26.62)
  - Colgate, Mary Evelyn (VC 1879), Fund (Folder 26.63)
  - Colgate, Mary Evelyn (VC 1879), Gift of (Folder 26.64)
  - Colman, Fanny Lovell (VC 1871), Memorial (Folder 26.65)
  - Colman, Howard D., Library Fund (Folder 26.66)
  - Contemporary Club, Gift of (Folder 26.67)
  - Corning, L. Augusta (VC Spec. 1865-1866) and Anna Corning (VC Spec. 1867-1868) Fund (printed by Rudge, 1936, Kalkhoff Press, 1945) (Folder 26.68)
  - Coykendall, Samuel D., Gift of (Folder 26.69)
  - Critchley, Bertha (VC 1887), In memory of (Folder 26.70)
  - Cummings, Louise D., Gift of (Folder 26.71)
  - Cushing, Florence M., (VC 1874), Fund (printed by Rudge, 1933) (Folder 26.72)
  - Cutler, Ruth (VC 1912), Bequest of (Folder 26.73)
  - Cutting, Elizabeth B. (VC 1893), From the library of (Folder 26.74)
  - Czechoslovak Legation, Gift of (Folder 26.75)
  - Daggett, Susan E., Gift of (Folder 26.76)
  - Dana, E. Elizabeth, Memorial fund (Folder 26.77)
  - Daughters of the American Revolution, Vassar Chapter (Folder 26.78)
  - Dean, Willard L., (printed by Rudge, 1932) (Folder 26.79)
  - Denny, Lillian Murdock (VC 1915), Bequest of (Folder 26.80)
  - Dimock, Mrs. Elizabeth Jordan (VC 1879), Gift of [2 variants] Dimock, George E. (Folder 26.81)
  - Drake, Durant, From the library of (Folder 26.82)
  - Dwight, William B., From the library of (Folder 26.83)
  - Easley, Frances Virginia, In memory of (engraved by Black Starr and Frost- Gorham, Inc., 1937) (Folder 26.84)
  - Eidlitz, Dorothy Meigs See: Salmon, Lucy M., In memory of
  - Ely Mathematical Fund (Folder 26.85)
  - English Book Club (Folder 26.86)
  - Estes, Benjamin, Memorial fund (Folder 26.87)
  - Fiftieth Anniversary, Gift of Class of ____ (Folder 26.88)
  - Finch, Charlotte Elizabeth, Fund in memory of (printed by Todd) (Folder 26.89)
  - Folger, Emily C.J. (VC 1879), fund [no plate] (Folder 26.90)
  - Fox, Helen Morgenthau (VC 1905) [no plate] (Folder 26.91)
  - French Government, Gift of (Folder 26.92)
  - Gift of... [variants] See also: Vassar College Library, Gift of (Folder 26.93)
  - Gift of the Alumnae (Folder 26.94)
  - Gift of the publisher See also: Vassar College Library, Gift of the publisher (Folder 26.95)
  - Gift to the Vassar College Library (Folder 26.96)
  - Gleason, Mrs. Mabel B., Gift of (Folder 26.97)
  - Goldmark, Emil, In honor of (Folder 26.98)
  - Greenough, Chester Noyes, Library fund (designed by Merrymount Press) (Folder 26.99)
  - Hadley, Arthur Twining See: Taft, William Howard
  - Hadley, Helen Morris (VC 1883), In memory of (designed and printed by Yale University Press) (Folder 26.100)
  - Harper, James, In memory of (Folder 26.101)
  - Hill, William Bancroft, Gift of (Folder 26.102)
  - Hispanic Society of America, Gift of (Folder 26.103)
  - Houghton, Elizabeth G. (VC 1873), Gift of House Libraries See: Vassar College House Libraries (Folder 26.104)
  - Howe, Mrs. Lucien (VC 1882) Gift of (Folder 26.105)
  - Huntington, Henry E., Library, Compliments of (1936) (Folder 26.106)
  - Hutchinson, Ruth Gillette, From the library of (Folder 26.107)
  - Jenckes, Harriet Morse (VC 1884), In memory of (Folder 26.108)
  - Josselyn, Olivia, Hall (Folder 26.109)
  - Justice, Anna Justice Fund (designed by M.C. Green) (Folder 26.110)
  - Justice, Henry Justice Fund (superceded by Anna Justice Fund, same design) (Folder 26.110)
  - Kendrick, G.A. [personal; used with Vassar College Library plate] (Folder 26.111)
  - Kendrick Fund (printed by Todd) [3 variants] (Folder 26.112)
  - Kennerly, Mitchell, This book was published by Kennerly, Mitchell, Gift of (Folder 26.113)
  - King, Gertrude Besse, Fund (Folder 26.114)
  - Kohn, Solomon H., Memorial Fund (Folder 26.115)
  - Kutzner, Anna (VC 1911), 1911 honors (Folder 26.116)
  - Lammert, Florence Cramton, From the library of (Folder 26.117)
  - Lammert, Olive M. (VC 1915), Library [personal] (Folder 26.118)
  - Lapham, Arioch and Sylvia, Endowment Fund (Todd, 1936; Goudy type, printed by Coggeshall, 1946) (Folder 26.119)
  - Lapham, Ella Caroline (VC 1876), Bequest of (Folder 26.120)
  - LeClear, Bonnie Wallace, Memorial Fund (Todd, 1936; Kalkhoff Press, 1941) (Folder 26.121)
  - Librarian's Fund (printed by Kalkhoff Press, 1941) (Folder 26.122)
  - Loewenstein, Maurice Fl, Memorial Fund (designed by Merrymount Press, 1933) (Folder 26.123)